# TARIQ ALREHILY

18 Kenilworth Park, Harold's Cross, Dublin 6w, Ireland. | +353 (0) 87 112 9360 | Tariqalrehily@gmail.com

## **SUMMERY**

Motivated and self-starter with more than four years professional experience as an operation analyst and computer engineer, who has developed a mature and responsible approach to any task I undertake. As postgraduate student in IT field, I demonstrate understanding of troubleshooting, user support, data management, cloud computing and others. Seeking a new position to develop my knowledge and share my skills.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### March 2015 - Present

# **Operations Analyst**

CPL @ FACEBOOK, Dublin (Ireland)

- Investigate and resolve issues that are reported on Instagram and Facebook such as requests for account support
- Gather, analyze and utilize relevant data to develop ways to improve the overall user experience on the site
- Respond to user inquiries with high quality, speed, empathy and accuracy
- Use problem solving skills to resolve large and complex business problems
- Recognize trends and patterns, and escalate issues to the global team
- Quality Auditors Team and Quality POC

#### Oct 2010 - Sept 2011

# Computer Engineer

Jerasy computer and communication services, Riyadh (Saudi Arabia)

- Maintaining a computing environment by identifying system requirements
- Daily maintenance, monitoring and support of the IT Infrastructure
- Building and maintenance of PC's and basic Active Directory
- Provide support for internal IT systems and stuff
- Basic server maintenance

### Sept 2008 - Sept 2010

## Data Entry and Receptionist

Al Dakhil Plaza Hotel, Medina (Saudi Arabia)

- Dealing with all customers' enquiries
- · Administer reservations and cancellations
- Contacting agencies to sale and promote the hotel services

#### **EDUCATION**

## Sept 2014 - Jan 2015

## **Cloud Computing**

Dublin City University (DCU), Dublin (Ireland)

Cloud Architecture, System Software, Data Management and Visualisation and Professional and Research Practice.

(Completed 30 Credit toward Master degree)

## Sept 2011 - Sept 2013

# Master of Science in Information Systems Processes (Level 9)

Waterford Institute of Technology (WIT), Waterford (Ireland)

Business Proc. Analysis and Design, Information Systems and Project Management (SAP), Ethics and e-privacy, Human Centred Inf. Systems, and Supply Chain Int. Tech.

**Dissertation Title:** Social Networking Applications for Mobile Phones Enhance The Communication Tools for Social Networking Activities.

June 2004 - May 2009

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (Level 8)

Taibah University (TU), Medina (Saudi Arabia)

Advanced Operating Systems, Software Engineering, Assembly Language, Programming, Computer Graphic, Network Security, Data Base Management, and Information Center Management.

## PERSONAL SKILLS

languages Arabic / Native English / Excellent

Accomplishment Book title: Social Applications Enhanced The Communication Tools for Social Activities.

Published by LAP LAMBERT publishing, publish on 11<sup>th</sup> November 2016.

Technical skills • HTML, CSS, JavaScript and SQL

• System software and hardware support

• Office Applications (MS word, MS Excel and MS power point)

• Cloud computing concepts

• Basic network configuring

Communication skills • Excellent skills working in a technical environment

• Good at communication with customers in quality, speed, empathy and accuracy

• Good at communicate with colleagues

Excellent teamwork

Organizational skills Very organized, responsible, quick learner, hard worker, multi-tasking, presentation skill

and motivated to work. Ability to work in a team and individual work.

Interests Software consultant, software sales, customer service, programming, business

development, data analyst, user software and hardware support, cloud computing, social

media and IT Business.

Projects The main research objectives were to assess changes in communication resulting from the

use of social networking applications. This was achieved through a primary online survey that was administered through Social media. The respondents were carefully selected university students who were meant to provide response for addressing the research questions. The findings show improvements in communication on mobile phones resulting

from social networking applications usage.

References Available upon request.